American Society of Newspaper Editors Records
American Society of Newspaper Editors Records
1964-1966
American Society of Newspaper Editors.
0.5 linear ft.
The records relate entirely to the organization's 1966 annual meeting in Montreal, Canada.
Correspondence on the panel discussions, program and speakers (J.G.Diefenbaker, Lyndon Johnson, Jean LeSage, Robert S. McNamara and Lester B. Pearson)
148812
Biographical History
The American Society of Newspaper Editors was founded in 1922. The first president was Casper Yost of the St. Louis Globe-Democrat.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The American Society of Newspaper Editors Records consists of Correspondence relating entirely to the organization's 1966 annual meeting in Montreal, Canada.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is subdivided into three groups: Panel discussions, Preparation and publicity, and Speakers. Within these three subseries, material is arranged alphabetically by name and/or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Diefenbaker, John G., 1895-1979.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; McNamara, Robert S., 1916-; Pearson, Lester B.; American Society of Newspaper Editors.; Journalism, Societies, etc.; Newspaper editors, United States, Societies, etc.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in 1966.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Panel discussions
    - Communist China, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Economic relations, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Program suggestions, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - Separatism, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Stand-by program, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Weekend papers, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Youth program, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Preparation and publicity
    - The Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Canadian government, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Drapeau, Mayor Jean and Jean Dupire, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Press and microphone chairmen, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Queen Elizabeth Hotel, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Speakers
    - Diefenbaker, J.G., 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Johnson, Lyndon (President), 1965 (Box 1)
    - Lesage, Jean, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - McNamara, Robert S., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Pearson, Lester B., 1965-1966 (Box 1)